

PROFILE

Data Analyst with Proven Problem-Solving and Project Management Skills

KEY SKILLS

6+ Years experience with customer service, sales and marketing 5+ Years measuring success by KPI's, analytics and A/B testing 3+ Years pitching, planning, and executing segmentation strategies, campaigns and automated flows 3+ Years using data analysis techniques, making data-driven decisions and project management

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Excel
- · Github
- · Big Query
- · SQL
- · Google Cloud
- · Google Analytics

CERTIFICATIONS

2019 Google Analytics for Beginners 2020 Advanced Google Analytics 2023 Udacity SQL for Data Analysis

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BIOLOGY

University of California, Santa Cruz 2013 - 2018

REFERENCES

CMO - Namisha Bahl Ecommerce Manager - Colin Zeal Phone numbers given upon request.

SARAH PENA

(626) 940-9109 PORTLAND, OR

sarahpena805@gmail.com

github.com/data-analysis-sarah-pena/Portfolio_Projects

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

- Data Analysis | Data-driven Decision Making |
 Project Management
- A/B Testing for Marketing Campaigns | Statistical Analysis (Regression, Hypothesis Testing)
- SQL Fundamentals | Excel (Pivot Tables, Data Visualization)
- Email Scraping | Data Cleaning for Accuracy and Reliability

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR EMAIL MARKETING MANAGER

Mogul, Remote 2021 - 2022

- Developed and implemented data-driven marketing strategies, resulting in a 20% increase in website traffic and a 3% boost in conversion rates within six months.
- Created up-sell and cross-sell opportunities by segmenting the audience using metadata such as browsing behavior, order history, location, and website behavior to achieve a 25% higher click-through rate and 15% B2B conversion rate from current B2C users.

EMAIL MARKETING ANALYTICS SPECIALIST

Fully, Remote 2020 - 2022

- Increased audience by 78% with over 200,000 active subscribers in North America by capturing emails through website pop-ups, fly-outs, banners, and A/B testing copy, images and timing.
- Implemented cohort analysis to understand customer lifetime value (CLV) and purchase patterns, which led to the identification of high-value customer segments and increased marketing investment efficiency by 20%.

SALES SUPERVISOR

HelloFresh, Santa Ana, CA 2018 - 2019

- Produced new business leads with direct and indirect marketing initiatives, generating an average of 500 new leads per month.
- Exceeded 12 sales per week estimating an average of \$3M in total annual revenue.